<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="18"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[LESSON PLAN




                                              2 hours]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Table of Contents







        WEEK 1 .................................................................................................................................................................. 3

        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument ....................................................................................................................................................3
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument ......................................................................................................................................4


        WEEK 2 ................................................................................................................................................................. 5

        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument .......................................................................................................................................5
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument ......................................................................................................................................6



        WEEK 3 ................................................................................................................................................................. 7
        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug.........................................................................................................................................7

        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug ........................................................................................................................................8


        WEEK 4 .................................................................................................................................................................9

        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug.........................................................................................................................................9
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug ...................................................................................................................................... 10



        WEEK 5 ................................................................................................................................................................ 11
        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System .................................................................................................................................11

        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ...............................................................................................................................12


        WEEK 6 ................................................................................................................................................................13

        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ................................................................................................................................13
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System .............................................................................................................................. 14



        WEEK 7 ................................................................................................................................................................15
        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ...........................................................................................................................................15
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ..........................................................................................................................................16



        WEEK 8 ................................................................................................................................................................17

        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ...........................................................................................................................................17
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ..........................................................................................................................................18







        2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                              week 1




        Target Vocabulary:

        Calm- Peaceful- Village- Argument - Buggy eyes- Wise - Genius –Strange – Climb - Ladder
        Materials:

        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -Boardmarkers
        Extras:
        Stopwatch - Bell or a whistle - Extra A4 Paper - Pencils

        Warm up (5 min):

        Show students the cover of Chapter 1. Ask them to talk about the characters and what the story might be about.
        Read the title and write the title “A Journey to The Solar System” on the board. Ask students
               – Are you interested in space?

               – What do you know about the Solar System?
               – Would you like to have a journey to the Solar System?
               – Who would you like to go to the space with?

        Presentation (15min):

        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.

        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.
        Ask students to underline any unknown vocabulary item. Set up a routine for who will read the text, so that each
        week different students get a chance to read.

        Practice(10min):
        Ask students which vocabulary items they don’t know. Using the smart board application, explain the word
        meanings to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.
        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.

               – What is the title of Episode 1? Who is having an argument?
               – What is the argument about?
               – Who are the main characters in the story?

               – Who is your favourite character? Why?

        End of the Lesson(10 min):
        1. Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find the
        meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting. Students
        are allowed to use a dictionary.

        2. Homework. Activity Book pages 4,5,6.

        Extra Activities:
        1. Students can pick a card from the box and talk about the character. They can continue the story or describe
        the physical appearance. (Axebug-Dung Beetle-Ladybug- Butterfly-Bee-Snake-Spider-Worm- Caterpillar).
          W1L1E1001

        2. Find your way through the jungle below.    W1L1E1002




                                                                                                               3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                              week 1




        Warm up (5min):

        Make a spelling bee competition with the underlined words from the previous lesson.  Use target vocabulary as
        extension. Ask each student one word.

        Presentation(10min):

        Listen to the audio and read the episode again. Ask what students understand from the story. Then, talk about
        the argument between Ladybug and Dung Beetle. What do they think of the argument? Write down their
        thoughts on the board.

        Practice(15min):
        Depending on the size of your class, put students into groups of 5. Each group will choose a piece of paper from
        the box. On the papers, write “flat” or “round”. The group members are supposed to suppport their point of view.
        If it says “flat” on the paper, they should find some arguments to support that the world is flat.
        The students can use the internet to find arguments. They can use the class computer in turns to carry out their
        search, but mainly they should discuss in their groups to come up with some arguments.
        Also, tell the groups to think about how they would respond to other groups’ arguments.
        It is very important to give them enough time for preperation.


        End of the lesson(10min):
        1. When the time is up, pick two groups and start the debate. You will be the moderator. Help them carry on with
        the debate. Do not attend to their language mistakes during the debate.
        At the end of the debate, ask other class members to vote for which group was more convincing.
        2. Homework. Activity Book pages 7,8,9

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Ask students to retell what happens in Episode 1 in their own words very briefly.
        2.  Match, cut and glue activity. Photocopy the sheet and have fun!   W1L2E1004

        Project:

        Make up an AxeJuice in class. Ask the students to bring some fruits and a fruit press. (Or bring your own.) In
        pairs, ask students to prepare a mixed fruit coctail in class that looks like Axebugs Fruit Juice. They can present
        it in the class. Take some photos during the activity and make a poster of it to hang it on the class walls. If you
        don’t have time in class, aske them to prepare it at home and take a video of it so you can present it to the class
        later on.



























        4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                             week 2




        Target Vocabulary:

        Calm- Peaceful- Village- Argument - Buggy eyes- Wise - Genius –Strange – Climb - Ladder

        Materials:
        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -Laptop

        Extras:

        Photocopies

        Warm up(5min):
        Show students some flashcards or pictures which you have prepared before that have different vehicles on them.
        (Space Shuttle, Plane, Helicopter, Pirate Ship etc) Ask them to describe these vehicles. Ex. The Plane has large
        wings.

        Presentation(10min):

        Write adjectives on the board for students to describe ‘ZZZ55’. Ask them which features does Axebug’s ship
        have. Write the adjectives on the board.

        High, low, dangerous, fun, adventuruous, far, huge, fantastic, rough, heavy, clean, dirty, amazing, wide, modern,
        noisy, curved.

        Practice(15min):

        Divide the class into groups of 4 or 5 for role – play. Ask them to prepare the dialogue sheet. Later they can come
        together with their group and practice their play.


        End of the lessson(10min):
        1.  Ask groups to present their dialogues to the class.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 10,11

        Extra activities:

        1.  Use target vocabulary from Activity Book. Ask students to use the words to build up sentences.  W1L3E1005
        2.  For this activity, allow students to use their dictionary. In pairs, they can complete the Synonym Sheet.
               W1L3E1006































                                                                                                               5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                             week 2




        Warm up(5min):

        Photocopy enough Axebug masks to your classroom. Enter the class with a mask and ask them who it is. Hand
        them out. Allow them to decorate their mask and hide it until the end of the lesson. 1.6

        Presentation(15min):

        1.  Ask students whether they know what an “idiom” is. You can give some examples from students’ mother
            tongue. You can also use the video in the link to explain students why it is important to learn idioms.








        2.  Write the idioms / expressions on the board. In pairs, ask students 4 short dialogues to use these idioms /
            expression in a sentence. Then, they will share their dialogues with the class.

        Has a screw loose  -  score you off  -  stinky smell  -  stubborn as a mule  -  come hell or high water

        Practice(20min):
        Students are to put their mask on. Pick one student and allow them to wait outside. Then, make all the students
        take their mask off and take one of the students mask to put on your face. Have your student come in and guess
        whose mask it is on your face.

        End of the lessson(5min):
        Check the Activity Book’s of each student.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Hand out the photocopies and ask what’s missing in Axebug’s room? Tell them that the comics can be their
            guide.   W1L4E1007
        2.  Use these speaking tasks to engage students with the language.

               – Which character is most similar to you? Why?
               – Think of a different title for the story. If not ‘The Argument’, then what can it be?

               – Any of the characters similar to a person who you already know?
               – What do you think is going to happen next?

        Project:
        See if they can do two things at the same time. Ask students to climb up a ladder or stairs while reading Episode
        1. If you don’t have time in class, ask them to prepare it at home and take a video of it so you can present it to
        the class later on.






















        6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 3




        Target Vocabulary

        Spaceship – Housefly – Proof – Decision – Kidding – Knowledge – Adventuruous – Journey -  Take off – Space
        Suit  - Control Panel - Launch


        Materials
        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -Laptop

        Extras
        Photocopies

        Warm up(5min):

        1.  Ask the students if the have met anyone who made Incredibe Inventions. Then, expand the topic with meeting
            a Professor or someone who studies hard or researches a lot.

        2.  Ask them to give Information about him/her. Write some key words on the board to help them describe. Do
            they sound like Axebug or not? Why?

        Presentation(10min):

        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.

        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.
        Ask students to underline any unknown vocabulary item.

        Practice(15min):

        Ask students which vocabulary items they don’t know. Using the smart board application, explain the word
        meanings to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.

        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.
               – What is the title of Episode 2? What is the main idea?
               – Who is launching?

               – What is your favourite part about it?
        End of the lessson(10min):
        1.  Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find
            the meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting.
            Students are allowed to use a dictionary.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 12,13.

        Extra activities:
        1.  Tell us about your last holiday by answering the questions below.   W2L1E1009

               – Which transport did you use?
               – Did you pack a bag?

               – What did you take with you?
               – Did you see how the engine fired up or not?
        2.  Color the Picture.   W2L1E1010







                                                                                                               7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 3




        Warm up (5min):

        Introduce some different jobs and their uniforms. Use some flashcards or colored printouts. Talk about why
        uniforms change according to jobs. Why don’t they wear the same thing?  Discuss. Then, ask students to try to
        describe the space suit of Axebug.

        Presentation (15min):
        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.
        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.

        Practice (15min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.


        End of the lessson (10min):
        1.  When they are finished with dialogue practice, draw a space suit on the board. Ask them to draw their own
            space suit too. When they finish, ask them why they drew it that way. End the lesson with the discussion.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 14,15

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Ask them to draw a firefighter working in space. What kind of a spacesuit would he/she have? Why? Discuss
            in class.  W2L2E1011
        2.  Hand them out an alliteration sheet. Give them examples and practice together.  W2L2E1012

        Project:

        Ask students to research some English jokes and their history. Tell them to make a small PPT presentation and
        present it to the class. If you don’t have time in class, ask them to prepare it at home and take a video of it so
        you can present it to the class later on.







































        8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 4




        Target Vocabulary

        Spaceship – Housefly – Proof – Decision – Kidding – Knowledge – Adventuruous – Journey -  Take off – Space
        Suit  - Control Panel - Launch


        Materials
        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -Laptop

        Extras
        Colored pencils – Craft paper - Photocopies

        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students which super cartoon character they like? Why? Ask which super powers are the most attracting
        ones.

        Presentation (15min):

        Allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences. While reading, ask them which super powers do they think the
        characters might have.

        Practice(10min):
        Ask them to open their Activity book page 17. Complete question 8 together.


        End of the lessson (15min):
        1.  Using craft paper, make your own super power logo together. While decorating ask them what features it
            has. End the lesson by sticking them on the wall or board.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 16,17

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Complete the worksheet below and find the secret message. A secret message transmitting from space ship!
            Let’s find out what is it. Calculate equations and match letter with solution.  W2L3E1013
        2.  Hide 10 cards that have words from Axebug Comics in the classroom. Ask students to find the cards and
            write sentences on the board using those cards.   W2L3E1014
































                                                                                                               9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 4




        Warm up (5min):

        Prepare a suitcase that has interesting objects in it. Enter the classroom with the suitcase and tell students that
        it is a bag which you prepared to take space.  Take out the objects one by one and ask them what they are, why
        do they think you are taking it etc.

        Presentation (10min):
        Write the words below on the board. Ask students where and when they wear those specific outfits. Ask them
        if they think they will need these while packing their bags to space.
        PYJAMAS – SCHOOL UNIFORM – JEANS – JACKET – T SHIRT – TUXEDO – WEDDING DRESS – BIKINI

        Practice (15min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.


        End of the Lesson (10min):
        Check the Activity Book’s of each student.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Give students the prinout below. Ask students to complete the wordsearch.  W2L4E1015

        2.  Ask students if they would pack their bags and go somewhere when they receive an invitation from a wise
            person? Why? Why not?  W2L4E1016

        Project:

        Ask students to design and make a space suit from fabric or recycled materials. If you don’t have time in class,
        ask them to prepare it at home and take a video of it so you can present it to the class later on.













































        10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 5




        Target Vocabulary

        Dizzy –Spectacular- Locate-Solar System-Planet-Revolve Ray- Satellite

        Materials
        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -Laptop

        Extras

        Photocopies – bell or whistle - stopwatch

        Warm up (5min):
        Start the lesson by asking them if they know any facts about Earth. Then, read the ones below.
               – There is only one natural satellite of the Earth

               – Earth is the only planet not named after a god
               – Earth is the only planet in our solar system known to support life
               – Earth orbits around the sun


        Presentation (15min):
        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.
        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.

        Practice (10min):
        Ask students which vocabulary items they don’t know. Using smart board application, explain the word meanings
        to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.
        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.

               – What is the title of Episode 3?
               – Where are they heading to?
               – What can you say about the earth?

               – Which part is your favourite? Why?

        End of the lesson (10min):
        1.  Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find
            the meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting.
            Students are allowed to use a dictionary.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 18, 19.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Use craft materials to make a big ‘Earth Poster’ with the students. Divide them into three or four groups to
            decorate their own posters. Ask them to write some facts aswell as drawing and coloring an earth. Present
            it outside the classroom.  W3L1E2017
        2.  Hand them out the sheet below. Ask them to cut out the mixed facts and opinions to glue to the right
            column.  W3L1E2018








                                                                                                               11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 5




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students if they have ever heard someone saying ‘Oh my Gosh!’ If they don’t know what it means, explain
        it to them. Later, ask them to build some daily sentences using ‘Oh my Gosh’.

        Presentation (15min):

        Allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences. While reading, ask them more about the solar system.

        Practice (10min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.


        End of the Lesson (10min):
        1.  Ask students to open their Activity Book pg 20. Complete question 5 together.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 20, 21.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Ask the students how they panic when they are in a tough situation. What do they do to overcome the
            problem? Why?  W3L2E2019

        2.  Play a sentence game. Write the target vocabulary on the board. Ask students to build sentences using the
            words. Just before they start, give them a specific topic from the box below. Choose one you want them to
            talk about so they don’t have time to think. Ask them to create sentences spontaneously in 5 seconds. If one
            of them can’t, move to the next student.   W3L2E2020
        TOPICS: WEATHER – FRIENDSHIP – ARGUMENTS – HOLIDAY – FUTURE

        Project:
        Ask them to make a funfact brochure about the sun. Tell them specific information like:

               – 4 page brochure (use A4 paper and fold it like a brochure)
               – Neatly written

               – Decorate it, use pictures
               – Write 5 facts about the sun































        12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 6




        Target Vocabulary

        Dizzy –Spectacular- Locate-Solar System-Planet-Revolve Ray- Satellite

        Materials
        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -Laptop

        Extras

        Photocopies

        Warm up (5min):
        Start the lesson with Information about the Earth. Tell them how big earth is. Ask students ‘If you can put
        1300000 Earths in Sun, how many do you think you can put in Mars?’

        Presentation (10min):
        Watch the video in the classroom and ask the questions to discuss.
               – What do you think about the video?

               – What would happen to Earth if the Sun was smaller?
               – What is another name for Mars?

               – Name a blue planet?
               – What does the video say about ‘Two suns’?

        Practice (15min):
        Hand them out the star sheet. Ask them to check the words very carefully. From a box, pick the little papers
        which have the words written one by one. Whoever finds the same word on their sheet gets to color it. If they
        color it first, they also get to make a sentence with that word.

        Endof the lesson (10min):
        1.  Hand them out the worksheet about the video and answer the questions together.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 22, 23.


        Extra Activities:
        1.  Ask them to use their wordbanks to complete the chart below. Fill in the blanks with a word that starts with
            the letter. All the words must start with the letter given.  W3L3E2021
        2.  Ask them to try to spell the words below in the classroom. Make a small competition in the classroom.
            Whoever gets all the lists correct, wins!  W3L3E2022























                                                                                                              13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 6




        Warm up (5min):

        Show students the sticks and banners you prepared for the game you are going to play later on. Give two flags
        to each student. Hand them out and ask them to write Earth on one and Sun on the other.

        Presentation (15min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.

        Practice (15min):

        Ask the students to stick the banner to the wooden sticks that you handed. Then, make sure they have written
        Earth on one and Sun on the other. Later, divide them into groups and give them fun facts about sun or earth
        without saying that it is. They are suppose to guess if the fact is Earth’s or the Sun’s. Whichever group member
        gives the answer should put the banner up so that It’s their turn to speak. Give them points.

        End (5min):
        1.  Homework: Activity Book pages 24, 25.

        Project:

        Ask them to prepare a model Solar System at home. They can use recycled materials or boxes to build one.
        Display it in front of the classroom.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Use the photocopiable sheet to make a bookmark together.  W3L4E2023
        2.  Hand them out the sheet below. Ask them to write if they are Facts or Opinions.  W3L4E2024















































        14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 7




        Target Vocabulary

        Moon- Exist- Rock- Core- Form- Aprroximately- Dwarf Planet

        Materials
        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -Laptop

        Extras

        Photocopies

        Warm up (5min):
        Ask students what an ‘Emergency Call’ is.
               – Have you heard someone make an emergency call? What was it about?

               – What do you know about emergencies?
               – What do you do if there is an emergency situation?

        Presentation (15min):

        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.

        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.

        Practice (10min):
        Ask students which vocabulary items they don’t know. Using the flashcards and smart board application, explain
        the word meanings to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.
        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.
               – What is the title of Episode 4?

               – How many planets do you know?
               – What do you know about the moon?
               – What is your favorite part in Episode 4? Why?


        End (10min):
        1.  Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find
            the meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting.
            Students are allowed to use a dictionary.

        2.  Homework. Activity Book pages 26,27.
        Extra Activities:

        1.  Ask students why people wear glasses, sun glasses, 3d glasses, VR glasses. Discuss.
        2.  Ask students to find the action verb in the card and make a sentence with it. You have 1 minute to finish all
            of it. Every card is worth 10 points. Whoever gets the most point, wins!   W4L1E2026














                                                                                                              15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 7




        Warm up (5min):

        1.  Enter the class with a tray. Fill an ice cube tray with water and add different colors of food coloring to each
            unit. Stir with a toothpick and freeze. Fill a large, clear tank with warm water. Place the colored ice cubes in
            the water, two or three at a time. Students can observe them melting.
        2.  Give them some time if they want to try aswell.

        Presentation (15min):

        Give students the experiment sheet. Fill it in together.

        Practice (10min):
        Listen to the audio and read the episode again. Ask what students understand from the story. Then, talk about
        the planets. What do they think of the Information given? Write down their thoughts on the board.

        End of the lesson (10min):
        1.  Ask the students work in pairs to write a dialogue about an emergency moment. Give them extra vocabulary
            if necessary. Then, they can present it to the class.
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 28,29

        Project:

        Ask them to take a video at home with their family. Ask them to act like there is an emergency call and show
        what to do. (Family member don’t need to speak English) Ask them to bring it to school so you can present it
        to the class later on.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Give them Information about what cause or effect mean. Then write the chart on the board and ask the
            students to match the cause to the right effect.   W4L2E2027
        2.  Play Jenga. Take a box of jenga and stick or write the words below on it. Then, ask students to come to front
            one by one to play. Whoever picks each wood should start a story, and the next person should continue the
            story. Game ends when the tower falls.   W4L2E2028





































        16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 8




        Target Vocabulary

        Moon- Exist- Rock- Core- Form - Dwarf Planet-Amazing-Experience

        Materials
        Comics  - Activity Book – Dictionary – Smart board -LaptopExtras

        Extras

        Photocopies

        Warm up (5min):
        Hand out the poem snd read it with students. Ask the questions below.
               – Why do they say ‘Poor Pluto’?

               – What does ‘demoted mean’?
               – Have you heard of Eris or Ceres?
               – What is a dwarf planet?


        Presentation (15min):
        Watch the video in the classroom. Ask students to take notes while watching.  Watch it a couple of times if
        necessary.










        Practice (10min):
        Write the words on the board. Ask students to find the meanings from the dictionary to understand. Discuss the
        words in the classroom.
        DEMOTED – REVOKED – CONTROVERSY – BEYOND – ORBIT – DEBATE – APPEAR - QUALIFIED


        End of the lesson( 10min):
        1.  Handout the videosheets. Complete the worksheet with the students.  https://www.youtube.com/
            watch?v=KQyJOG9MMX8
        2.  Homework: Activity Book pages 30,31

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Ask students to use the big..as.. structure to describe an object in the classroom. Ex. My bag is as big as hers.

        2.  Give the handouts and ask students to complete the Wordsearch.  W4L3E2030

















                                                                                                              17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 8




        Warm up (5min):

        Use the words from the previous lesson to make a wordworm on the board. Each student should come up the
        board and write a word. When the next students comes, they should write a word starting with the end letter of
        the previous student. Try to play until the game ends!
        Ex. Appear – Revoked – Difference – Eris …

        Presentation (10min):

        Ask students to open the last page of the Comics. Discuss the questions.
               – Who is the robot on the monitor?
               – What do you think he wants?

               – What do you think his name is?
               – What do you think is going to happen on the next Chapter?

        Practice (10min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.

        End of the lesson (5min):

        Check the students Activity Books.

        Project:
        Ask the students to take a video of themselves trying to act like Dung Beetle. They can use some lines from the
        comics to make a small play.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Find the animals and scroll the words to the pictures.  W7L4E4056

        2.  Ask students if they want to revise any part of Chapter 1. Also ask them if they have any questions about the
            exam.





































        18]]></page></pages></Search>