<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="34"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[LESSON PLAN




                                              4 hours]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Table of Contents






        WEEK 1 .....................................................................3  WEEK 5 .................................................................. 19
        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument ...........................3  LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ................19

        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument ......................4  LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ..............20
        LESSON 3 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument ..........................5  LESSON 3 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ...............21

        LESSON 4 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument ......................6  LESSON 4 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ..............22


        WEEK 2 ....................................................................7  WEEK 6 ..................................................................23

        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug......................... 7  LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ...............23
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug ........................ 8  LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ..............24
        LESSON 3 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug ........................9  LESSON 3 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ..............25

        LESSON 4 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug ......................10  LESSON 4 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System ..............26


        WEEK 3 ................................................................... 11  WEEK 7 ..................................................................27

        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug.........................11  LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ..........................27
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug .......................12  LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets .........................28

        LESSON 3 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug .......................13  LESSON 3 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets .........................29
        LESSON 4 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug ......................14  LESSON 4 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ........................30



        WEEK 4 .................................................................. 15  WEEK 8 ...................................................................31
        LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug........................15  LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ...........................31
        LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug .......................16  LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets .........................32

        LESSON 3 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug .......................17  LESSON 3 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets .........................33
        LESSON 4 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug ......................18  LESSON 4 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets ........................34

























        2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                              week 1




        Warm up (5 min):

        Show students the cover of Chapter 1. Ask them to talk about the characters and what the story might be about.
        Read the title and write the title “A Journey to The Solar System” on the board. Ask students
               – Are you interested in space?

               – What do you know about the Solar System?
               – Would you like to have a journey to the Solar System?
               – Who would you like to go to the space with?


        Presentation (15min):
        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.
        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.
        Ask students to underline any unknown vocabulary item. Set up a routine for who will read the text, so that each
        week different students get a chance to read.

        Practice(10min):
        Ask students which vocabulary items they don’t know. Using the smart board application, explain the word
        meanings to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.
        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.

               – What is the title of Episode 1? Who is having an argument?
               – What is the argument about?
               – Who are the main characters in the story?

               – Who is your favourite character? Why?

        End of the Lesson(10 min):
        1. Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find the
        meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting. Students
        are allowed to use a dictionary.
        Extra Activities:

        Pick a card from the box and describe the character’s physical appearance.    W1L1E1001
        Find your way through the jungle below.    W1L1E1002


























                                                                                                               3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                              week 1




        Warm up (5min):

        Make a spelling bee competition with the underlined words from the previous lesson.  Use target vocabulary as
        extension. Ask each student one word.

        Presentation(10min):

        Listen to the audio and read the episode again. Ask what students understand from the story. Then, talk about
        the argument between Ladybug and Dung Beetle. What do they think of the argument? Write down their
        thoughts on the board.

        Practice(15min):
        Depending on the size of your class, put students into groups of 5. Each group will choose a piece of paper from
        the box. On the papers, write “flat” or “round”. The group members are supposed to suppport their point of view.
        If it says “flat” on the paper, they should find some arguments to support that the world is flat.
        The students can use the internet to find arguments. They can use the class computer in turns to carry out their
        search, but mainly they should discuss in their groups to come up with some arguments.
        Also, tell the groups to think about how they would respond to other groups’ arguments.
        It is very important to give them enough time for preperation.

        End of the lesson(10min):
        When the time is up, pick two groups and start the debate. You will be the moderator.  Help them carry on with
        the debate. Do not attend to their language mistakes during the debate.
        At the end of the debate, ask other class members to vote for which group was more convincing.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Who wants to sum up Episode 1?    W1L2E1003
        2.  Match, cut and stick the pairs.    W1L2E1004










































        4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                              week 1




        Warm up(5min):

        Show students some flashcards or pictures which you have prepared before. Make sure they have different type
        of food on them. (Hamburger, pizza, spaghetti, soups, salads  etc) Ask them to describe these food. Ex. The
        Spaghetti is delicious with tomato sauce.

        Presentation(15min):
        1.  Ask students to prepare a menu list for a space restaurant. Focus on these:

               – What type of food will be eaten there?
               – Will there be take away food?
               – What type of drinks will be there?

               – How much will it cost?
               – Would there be meat?

        2.  Ask them to prepare a menu sheet and share it with the class.

        Practice(10min):
        Ask students to open their Activity Book page 4 and 5. Complete the exercises together.

        End of the lessson(10min):
        Ask students to imagine what would Axebug, Dung Beetle or Ladybug like to eat or drink. Write the ideas on
        the board.

        Extra activities:

        1.  Find  target  vocabulary  from  the  Activity  Book/Question  10.  Use  the  words  to  build  up  5  sentences.
              W1L3E1005

        2.  Pair work: Use your dictionaries and complete the table with the synonyms of the words.    W1L3E1006









































                                                                                                               5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 1 | The Argument                                                              week 1




        Warm up(5min):

        Enter the classroom with a clean jar. Put the character names in it so every student gets to pick one. Go around
        the classroom and ask them to pick. After that, they are to explain the character in words. Ex. Confused, funny,
        happy etc.

        Presentation(15min):
        Take craft paper and character pictures to class. In pairs, ask students to make a character poster out of the
        words you gave them. Ask them to build sentences and write them on their poster. Ex. Axebug is tall He is funny
        and wise. Etc.

        Practice(15min):
        Complete pages 6 and 7 from the Activity book.

        End of the lessson(5min):

        Share page 7 exercise 6 answers in the classroom.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Find the missing pieces in Axebug’s room. Use the comics as your guide.   W1L4E1007
        2.  Answer the folowing questions.   W1L4E1008

               – Which character is most similar to you? Why?
               – Think of a different title for the story. If not ‘The Argument’, then what can it be?
               – Any of the characters similar to a person who you already know?

               – What do you think is going to happen next?

        Project:
        See if they can do two things at the same time. Ask students to climb up a ladder or stairs while reading Episode
        1. If you don’t have time in class, ask them to prepare it at home and take a video of it so you can present it to
        the class later on.





































        6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 2




        Warm up(5min):

        Show students some flashcards or pictures which you have prepared before. Make sure they have different type
        of food on them. (Hamburger, pizza, spaghetti, soups, salads  etc) Ask them to describe these food. Ex. The
        Spaghetti is delicious with tomato sauce.

        Presentation(15min):
        1.  Ask students to prepare a menu list for a space restaurant. Focus on these:

               – What type of food will be eaten there?
               – Will there be take away food?
               – What type of drinks will be there?

               – How much will it cost?
               – Would there be meat?

        2.  Ask them to prepare a menu sheet and share it with the class.

        Practice(10min):
        Ask students to open their Activity Book page 4 and 5. Complete the exercises together.

        End of the lessson(10min):
        Ask students to imagine what would Axebug, Dung Beetle or Ladybug like to eat or drink. Write the ideas on
        the board.

        Extra activities:

        1.  Find  target  vocabulary  from  the  Activity  Book/Question  10.  Use  the  words  to  build  up  5  sentences.
              W1L3E1005

        2.  Pair work: Use your dictionaries and complete the table with the synonyms of the words.    W1L3E1006









































                                                                                                               7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 2




        Warm up (5min):

        Photocopy enough Axebug masks to your classroom. Enter the class with a mask and ask them who it is. Hand
        them out. Allow them to decorate their mask and hide it until the end of the lesson.

        Presentation (15min):

        1.  Ask students whether they know what an “idiom” is. You can give some examples from students’ mother
            tongue. You can use the video in the link to explain students why it is important to learn idioms.









        2.  Write some idioms / expressions on the board. In pairs, ask students 4 short dialogues to use these idioms /
            expression in a sentence. Then, they will share their dialogues with the class.

        Practice(10min):

        Students are to put their mask on. Pick one student and allow them to wait outside. Then, make all the students
        take their mask off and take one of the students mask to put on your face. Have your student come in and guess
        whose mask it is on your face.

        End of the lessson (10min):
        Complete page 10 from the Activity Book.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Draw a firefighter working in space in his/her spacesuit. What kind of a spacesuit would he/she have? Discuss
            in class.   W2L2E1011

        2.  Practice the alliteration, then create your own using the structures given below.  W2L2E1012

        Project:
        Ask students to research some English jokes and their history. Tell them to make a small PPT presentation and
        present it to the class. If you don’t have time in class, ask them to prepare it at home and take a video of it so
        you can present it to the class later on.

































        8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 2




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students which type of music they like? Why? Also ask which music types are the most trendy ones?

        Presentation (10min):
        Allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences. While reading, ask them which type of music the characters might
        listen to.

        Practice (15min):

        Ask them to find the key words of Episode 1 in the classroom. Then, ask students to answer questions about
        music using those words.

               – What are your favorite bands or artists?
               – Do you download music or not? Why?

               – How often do you listen to music?
               – Do you use headphones? Why?
               – Do you listen to the radio?

               – Do you listen to music more when you are happy or sad?
               – What do you think about traditional music?

        End of the Lesson (10min):
        Complete page 11 from the Activity Book.


        Extra Activities:
        1.  Complete the sheet below and find the secret messsage. A secret message transmitting from space ship!
            Let’s find out what is it. Calculate equations and match letter with solution.   W2L3E1013
        2.  Find the hidden cards in the classroom and write sentences on the board about them.   W2L3E1014







































                                                                                                               9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 2




        Warm up (5min):

        Start the lesson by talking about your own free time activities. Then ask the students about their own free time.
        Use the questions below to help you.

               – Do you have free time during the day?
               – Do you like to watch movies?
               – What do you do in your free time?

               – What do you hate doing in your free time?

        Presentation (15min):
        Ask them if they would like to do skating or not. Then watch the video together and discuss.











        Practice (10min):
        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.

        End of the lesson (10min):
        Check the Activity Book’s of each student. Meanwhile, students can practice another dialogue.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Find the given words in the wordsearch puzzle.   W2L4E1015
        2.  Imagine that you are invited somewhere with a wise person from your town. Would you pack your bags and
            go? Why? Why not?   W2L4E1016

        Project:
        Ask students to design and make a space suit from fabric or recycled materials. If you don’t have time in class,
        ask them to prepare it at home and take a video of it so you can present it to the class later on.































        10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 3




        Warm up (5min):

        1.  Ask the students if the have met anyone who made Incredibe Inventions. Then, expand the topic with meeting
            a Professor or someone who studies hard or researches a lot.

        2.  Ask them to give Information about him/her. Write some key words on the board to help them describe. Do
            they sound like Axebug or not? Why?

        Presentation (10min):

        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.

        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.
        Ask students to underline any unknown vocabulary item.

        Practice (15min):

        Ask students which vocabulary items that they don’t know. Using the smart board application, explain the word
        meanings to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.

        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.
               – What is the title of Episode 2? What is the main idea?
               – Who is launching?

               – What is your favourite part about it?

        End of the Lesson (10min):
        1. Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find the
        meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting. Students
        are allowed to use a dictionary.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Pair work: Decorate a big ‘Earth Poster’ and color it. Then, give some Information about it.   W3L1E2017
        2.  Cut out the mixed facts and opinions. Stick them to the right column in the chart.   W3L1E2018




































                                                                                                               11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 3




        Warm up (5min):

        Introduce some different jobs and their uniforms. Use some flashcards or colored printouts. Talk about why
        uniforms change according to jobs. Why don’t they wear the same thing. Discuss. Then, ask students to try to
        describe the space suit of Axebug.

        Presentation (10min):
        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.
        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.

        Practice (15min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.


        Endof the lesson (10min):
        When they are finished with dialogue practice, draw a space suit on the board. Ask them to draw their own space
        suit too. When they finish, ask them why they drew it that way. End the lesson with the discussion.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Suppose that you are in a tough situation. How do you react? What do you do to overcome the problem?
              W3L2E2019
        2.  Make sentences spontaneously in 5 seconds by using the topics Weather, Friendship, Arguments, Holiday
            and Future.    W3L2E2020

        Project:
        Ask them to make a funfact brochure about the sun. Tell them specific information like:
               – 4 page brochure (use A4 paper and fold it like a brochure)

               – Neatly written
               – Decorate it, use pictures

               – Write 5 facts about the sun

































        12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 3




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students which super cartoon character they like? Why? Also ask which super powers are the most
        attracting ones?

        Presentation (10min):

        Allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences. While reading, ask them which super powers do they think the
        characters have?

        Practice (15min):
        Ask them to open their Activity book pages 12,13. Complete the exercises together.

        End of the Lesson(10min): Using craft paper, make your own super power logo together. While decorating ask
        them what features it has. End the lesson by sticking them on the wall or board.


        Extra Activities:
        1.  Complete the chart below with a word that starts with the letter given. Use your wordbanks as your guide.
              W3L3E2021
        2.  Spell the words correctly.  W3L3E2022

























































                                                                                                              13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 3




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask students if they are interested in planes. Continue the topic by asking company names of planes.
               – Have you ever been on a plane before?
               – How did you feel? Was it fun?

               – Did you travel with different companies? Why?

        Presentation (15min):
        Handout the worksheets. Students are to create a plane company of their own. Tell them to write the details and
        share it with the class.

        Practice (10min):
        Complete pages 14,15 from the Activity Book.

        End (10min):

        Check the students Activity Books.

        Project:
        Ask them to prepare a model Solar System at home. They can use recycled materials or boxes to build one.
        Display it in front of the classroom.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Choose one of the the bookmarks and design your own.   W3L4E2023
        2.  Read the sentences and write ‘Fact’ or ‘Opinion’.   W3L4E2024















































        14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 4




        Warm up (5min):

        Prepare a suitcase that has interesting objects in it. Enter the classroom with the suitcase and tell students that
        you  prepared  a bag to take space.  Take out the objects one by one and ask them what they are, why do they
        think you are taking it etc.

        Presentation (10min):
        Write the words below on the board. Ask students where and when they wear those specific outfits. Ask them
        if they think they will need these while packing their bags to space.

        Practice (15min):
        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.

        End of the lesson (10min):

        Complete page 16 from the Activity book.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Why do people wear glasses, sun glasses, 3D glasses or VR glasses? Discuss.    W4L1E2025
        2.  Find the action verb in the card and make a sentence with it. You have 1 minute to finish all of it. Every card
            is worth 10 points. Whoever gets the most point, wins!    W4L1E2026






















































                                                                                                              15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 4




        Warm up (5min):

        Talk about the idioms they already know. Ask students the idioms they have seen in the comics. Let them explain
        what they are.

        Presentation (10min):

        Listen to the audio and read the episode again. Then, talk about what is happening?  Write down their thoughts
        on the board.

        Practice (15min):

        Divide the class into groups of 4 or 5 for role – play. Hand them out the dialogue sheet. Ask them to come
        together with their group and practice their play.


        End of the lessson( 10min):
        Ask groups to present their dialogues to the class. Also, ask them if they can capture any idioms in the dialogues.

        Project:
        Ask them to take a video at home with their family. Ask them to act like there is an emergency call and show
        what to do. (Family member don’t need to speak English) Ask them to bring it to school so you can present it
        to the class later on.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Read and match the causes to the effects on the board.    W4L2E2027
        2.  With your teacher take a box of jenga and stick or write the words on it. Then, ask students to come to front
            one by one to play. Whoever picks each wood should start a story, and the next person should continue the
            story. Game ends when the tower falls.     W4L2E2028













































        16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 4




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask them to get prepared for a game during the lesson. Give the details.
               – Prepare a list of review vocabulary words
               – Write each word on two small pieces of paper. That means writing the word twice.

               – Organize the pieces like bundles, 2 bundles, 2 sets of identical words.

        Presentation (10min):
        Continue by listening to the audio and reading the episode again. Then, talk about the what is happening?  Write
        down their thoughts on the board.

        Practice (15min):
        Divide the class into 2 teams. Get them to make creative team names.

               – Distribute each list of words to both teams. Every student on each team should have a paper.  Both teams
              have the same words.

               – When you call a word, 2 students should stand up from each team. The students must run to the blackboard
              and race to write a sentence using their word.

        End of the lesson (10min):

        The winner is the one with a correct and clearly written sentence. Call out the winner.
        Complete page 17 from the Activity Book

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Describe an object in the classroom. Use ‘as big as’ structure.   W4L3E2029
        2.  Find the given words in the wordsearch puzzle.   W4L3E2030











































                                                                                                              17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 2 | Meet Axebug                                                              week 4




        Warm up (5min):

        Show some books and novels to the students. Talk about who has read them.
               – Their authors
               – When they have read?

               – Did they like it or not? Why?

        Presentation (10min):
        Then ask them some questions about Axebug Comics.

               – Who is the main character in Axebug  Space Adventures?
               – Give some words that describe the main character?
               – Would you like to read another book from this author? Why?

               – Would this story be a good cartoon?
               – What is your favorite part so far?
               – Which character is the most similar one to you? Why?

        Practice (15min):

        Ask them if they have another title for the comics instead of ‘Axebug Space Adventure’? Then, ask them to
        prepare a title on colored cards or papers and present it to the class.


        End of the lesson (10min):
        Check the Activity Books of the students. Meanwhile handout the sheet. They are to complete the worksheet
        below. Match the books to the authors.
        Project:

        Ask the students to transfer something from and electronical device. Ask them to take a video of it. While taking
        the video they should explain what they are doing and how they are transferring it.  Share it in the classroom.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  What does antonyms mean? Given an example.   W4L4E2031
        2.  Find the words given in the wordsearch below.   W4L4E2032































        18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 5




        Warm up (5min):

        Start the lesson by asking them if they know any facts about the earth. Then, read the ones below.
               – There is only one natural satellite of the Earth.
               – Earth is the only planet not named after a god

               – Earth is the only planet in our solar system known to support life.
               – Earth orbits around the sun.

        Presentation (10min):

        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.

        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.

        Practice (15min):
        Ask students which vocabulary items they don’t know. Using the smart board application, explain the word
        meanings to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.
        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.
               – What is the title of Episode 3?

               – Where are they heading to?
               – What can you say about the earth?
               – Which part is your favourite?


        End of the Lesson (10min):
        1.  Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find
            the meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting.
            Students are allowed to use a dictionary.

        2.  Homework. Activity Book pages 4,5,6.
        Extra Activities:

        1.  Write a story of your own using the words given. (Find – kidding – Calm – Village – Town – Buggy Eyes –
            housefly – spaceship) The story must involve space, planets or Axebug.  W5L1E3033
        2.  Unscramble the words and write.  W5L1E3034




























                                                                                                              19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 5




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students if they have ever heard someone saying ‘Oh my Gosh!’ If they don’t know what it means, explain
        it to them. Later, ask them to build some daily sentences using ‘Oh my Gosh’.

        Presentation (10min):

        Allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences. While reading, ask them more about the solar system.

        Practice (15min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.


        End of the lesson (10min):
        Ask students to open their Activity Book page 20. Complete question 5 together.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  What can you control in life? How? Discuss in class.  W5L2E3035

        2.  Find the folowing words in the puzzle.  W5L2E3036

























































        20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 5




        Warm up (5min):

        Start the lesson with Information about the Earth. Tell them how big earth is. Ask students ‘If you can put
        1300000 Earths in Sun, how many do you think you can put in Mars .

        Presentation (15min):










        Watch the video in the classroom and ask the questions to discuss.

               – What do you think about the video?
               – Would it be good or bad to Earth if the Sun was smaller?
               – What is another name for Mars?

               – Name a blue planet?
               – What does the video say about ‘Two suns’?

        Practice (10min):
        Hand them out the star sheet. Ask them to check the words very carefully. From a box, pick the little papers
        which have the words written one by one. Whoever finds the same word on their sheet gets to color it. If they
        color it first, they also get to make a sentence with that word.

        End of the lesson (10min):
        Hand them out the worksheet about the video and answer the questions together.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Do you think Ladybug’s bring you luck? Why? Discuss in the class.   W5L3E3037
        2.  Watch the video about Ladybugs and discuss the words below.   W5L3E3038




































                                                                                                              21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 5




        Warm up (5min):

        Show the students the sticks and banners you prepared for the game you are going to play later on. Hand them
        out and ask them to write Earth on one and Sun on the other.

        Presentation (10min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.

        Practice (15min):

        Ask the students to stick the banner to the sticks that you handed. Then, make sure they have written Earth on
        one and Sun on the other. After that divide them into groups and give them fun facts about sun or earth without
        saying that it is. They are suppose to guess if the fact is Earth’s or the Sun’s. Whichever group member gives the
        answer they need to put their banner up so that It’s their turn to speak. Give them points.

        End( 10min):
        Check the students Activity Books.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Some children are named after ‘Space’. Do you know any? Can you think of any name.  Discuss.  W5L4E3039
        2.  Unscramble the words and write.  W5L4E3040






















































        22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 6




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students if we need the sun or the moon more. Write their thoughts on the board.

        Presentation (15min):
        Complete pages 18,19 from the Activity Book.

        Practice (10min):

        Complete page 20 from the Activity Book.
        End (10min):

        Write the question ‘Is feeling dizzy contagious?’ on the board. If they don’t know the meaning, explain. Then
        discuss it in the classroom.


        Extra Activities:
        1.  Take a shot at the trash can/box/etc. First ask a question to one. If s/he answers correctly then s/he can have
            a shot at the basket. If the Student gets the ball in the basket then s/he wins 2 points. If the S hits the basket
            without going inside then s/he wins 1 point. Play in teams.  W6L1E3041

        2.  Pair work: Practice the dialogue and perform.  W6L1E3042

























































                                                                                                              23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 6




        Warm up (5min):

        Talk about the moon. Ask students what they know about it.

        Presentation(15min):
        Watch the video and complete the video sheet together.










        Practice (10min):

        Complete the wordsearch. Then complete pages 21,22 from the Activity Book.

        End of the lesson (10min):
        Write the sentences on the  board. Then ask the students which sentence might belong to a character from the
        comics. Discuss.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Use the words from the moon wordsearch and  make sentences. Then, share it with the class.   W6L2E3043

        2.  Write out series of categories like professions (doctor, bus driver, etc.), animals, foods, actions (fishing,
            haircut, etc.) then divide the class into groups of 2. One student draws and the other guesses. Next turn, the
            guesser draws and drawer guesses.   W6L2E3044

        Project:
               – Organize the equipment that the students will use to design their future colonies.

               – Students can work by themselves or in groups of 2.
               – Get the students to think about their designs and project goals before they start building.
               – Begin building and ask them to take a video talking about it. Present it to the class.




































        24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 6




        Warm up (10min):

        Ask the students about how they like to spend their holiday.
               – How often do you go on holidays?
               – Where was you favorite holiday?

               – What do you eat/drink on holidays?
               – Do you watch TV/play with tab / play with your phone on holidays? Why?
               – What is something that you can’t go to holiday without?


        Presentation (15min):
        Ask students to create a speech.
               – You are going on a holiday with Dung Beetle! What are you going to do? Where are you going? What are you
              travelling with? Take notes and then share it with the class.

        Practice (10min):
        Complete pages  23,24 from the Activity Book.

        End of the lesson (5min):

        Use craft materials to draw your bus ticket with Dung Beetle.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Use the words below to make up a story in a minute.   W6L3E3045
        Sight seeing – rock climbing – museum – foreign – country – overseas – health – plane – suitcase – hotel – bus –
        sorry – change – train – backpack – ice-cream
        2.  PLAY CAPTURE! Find these words in Episode 3. The fastest one to capture all of them wins!  W6L3E3046

        Yippee – earth – imagine – star – energy – Gosh – open – answer – closest – revolving – rays – right – reach – first
        – big – impossible-heat – ready – center - you







































                                                                                                              25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 3 | The Solar System                                                         week 6




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students some questions to have a discussion.
        Have you ever
               – Had a surprise party

               – Had a broken leg or arm
               – Met a celebrity
               – Had a present that you hated

               – Played scavenger hunt before?

        Presentation (15min):
        Play Scavenger Hunt. Indoors or outdoors, place the objects for the students to seek. Use the printout as a
        checklist.

        Practice (10min):
        Complete page 25 from the Activity Book.

        End of the lesson (10min):

        Check the students Activity Book.

        Project:
        Watch an idioms video and talk about the meanings.










        Extra Activities:

        1.  Ask the students to use the words from the scavenger hunt to build up sentences.   W6L4E3047
        2.  Ask students to read through the data and solve the problems based on Radius.   W6L4E3048
































        26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 7




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask the students what an ‘Emergency Call’ is.
               – Have you heard someone make an emergency call? What was it about?
               – What do you know about emergencies?

               – What do you do if there is an emergency situation?

        Presentation (10min):
        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.
        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.

        Practice (15min):
        Ask students which vocabulary items they don’t know. Using the smart board applications, explain the word
        meanings to the students. Remember using your comic book as a context to explain words as well.
        Then, ask students to close their comics and then ask the following questions to check their comprehension.

               – What is the title of Episode 4?
               – How many planets do you know?

               – What do you know about the moon?
               – What is your favorite part in Episode 4? Why?

        End of the Lesson (10min):
        Dictionary Game. Write the underlined words on the board. Choose students to come to the board, find the
        meaning of the word and write the meaning. Use a stopwatch and a bell to make the activity exciting. Students
        are allowed to use a dictionary.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Do you like surprise parties?  Who would you like to have a surprise party with? Why? Discuss in class.
              W7L1E4049
        2.  Make up your own planet name. It can have a meaning or no meaning. Write it on a card and tell your
            classmates why you chose that word.   W7L1E4050































                                                                                                              27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 7




        Warm up (10min):

        1.  Enter the class with a tray. Fill an ice cube tray with water and add different colors of food coloring to each
            unit. Stir with a toothpick and freeze. Fill a large, clear tank with warm water. Place the colored ice cubes in
            the water, two or three at a time. Students can observe them melting.
        2.  Give them some time if they want to try aswell.

        Presentation (10min):

        Give students the experiment sheet. Fill it in together.

        Practice (10min):
        Listen to the audio and read the episode again. Ask what students understand from the story. Then, talk about
        the planets. What do they think of the Information given? Write down their thoughts on the board.

        End of the lesson (10min):
        Ask the students work in pairs to write a dialogue about an emergency moment. Give them extra vocabulary if
        necessary. Then, they can present it to the class.

        Project:
        Take a video at home with your family. Act like there is an emergency call and tell us what to do. (Family member
        don’t need to speak English) Ask them to bring it to school so you can present it to the class later on.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  What do you know about NASA? Give some information about it. Discuss with your classmates.   W7L2E4051

        2.  Find your way through the jungle below.   W7L2E4052

        Project:
        Ask students to do a bouncy ball experiment at home and take a video of it.
               – A large, heavy ball such as a basketball or soccer ball

               – A smaller, light ball such as a tennis ball or inflatable rubber ball

        Instructions:
        1.  Make sure you’re outside with plenty of room.

        2.  Carefully put the tennis ball on top of the basketball, holding one hand under the basketball and the other
            on top of the tennis ball.

        3.  Let go of both the balls at exactly the same time and observe what happens.
























        28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 7




        Warm up (10min):

        Read the poem to the students and discuss. Ask the questions below.
               – Why do they say ‘Poor Pluto’?
               – What does demoted mean?

               – Have you heard of Eris and Ceres?
               – What is a  dwarf planet?

        Presentation(10min):

        Watch the video in the classroom. Ask students to take notes while watching.  Watch it a couple of times if
        necessary.

        Why isn’t Pluto a Planet Anymore? Planet vs Dwarf Planet for Kids - FreeSchool - YouTube
        Practice (10min):

        Write the words on the board. Ask students to find the meanings from the dictionary to understand. Discuss the
        words in the classroom.

        DEMOTED – REVOKED – CONTROVERSY – BEYOND – ORBIT – DEBATE – APPEAR - QUALIFIED

        End of the lesson (10min):
        Handout the videosheets. Complete the worksheet with the students.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  Pair work: Make up a poem about Earth.  W7L3E4053
        2.  Complete the crossword below.  W7L3E4054













































                                                                                                              29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 7




        Warm up (10min):

        Use the words from the previous lesson to make a wordworm on the board. Each student should come up the
        board and write a word. When the next students comes, they should write a word starting with the end letter of
        the previous student. Try to play until the game ends!
        Ex. Appear – Revoked – Difference – Eris …

        Presentation (10min):

        Ask students to open the last page of the Comics. Discuss the questions.
               – Who is the robot on the monitor?
               – What do you think he wants?

               – What do you think his name is?
               – What do you think is going to happen on the next Chapter?

        Practice (10min):
        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.

        End of the lesson (10min):

        Complete page 26 from the Activity book.

        Project:
        Ask the students to take a video of themselves trying to act like Dung Beetle. They can use some lines from the
        comics to make a small play.

        Extra Activities:
        Use the words from Activity Book page 26 to build up some sentences.  W7L4E4055
        Find the animals and scroll the words to the pictures.  W7L4E4056







































        30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[LESSON 1 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 8




        Warm up (10min):

        Take a packet of M&M’s to the classroom. Ask a student to pick one. Then he/she should answer the same
        colored question from the chart below.

        Presentation (15min):

        Allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences. While reading, ask them more about the solar system.

        Practice (10min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.


        End of the lesson (5min):
        Use Rumba Shakers. Give it to the student to start shaking. Then ask them some questions. They are to shake
        and answer at the same time.
        Extra Activities:

        1.  Read each of them and circle the correct element. If necessary, use your science book.  W8L1E4057
        2.  Discussion: What is a gangster? Why is being  a gangster bad?  W8L1E4058
























































                                                                                                              31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[LESSON 2 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 8




        Warm up (5min):

        Talk about the planet names. Students are to make up a planet name of their own. Go around the classroom.

        Presentation (10min):
        Complete pages 27,28 from the Activity Book.

        Practice (15min):

        First, allow students to listen and follow from the book. Later, 3 students will be selected and assigned a character.
        Then, they will read aloud their sentences.

        While the students are reading, take notes of any pronunciation problems that you might notice.
        Ask students to underline any unknown vocabulary item. Then discuss them in the classroom.

        End of the lesson (10 min):
        Ask the folowing questions to make conversation.

               – Do you think there would be more planets?
               – What if Astronomers will find more? Discuss.

        Extra Activities:
        1.  Which planet other than earth is the most intereting planet? Why? Share your thoughts in the classroom.
              W8L2E4059
        2.  Find 5 differences between the pictures. Share it with the class.   W8L2E4060

        Project:

        Ask students to make a poster about Pluto using craft materials.
               – Use at least 3 facts about Pluto.

               – Use craft materials to decorate your A3 sized poster.
               – Printout images from the Internet if necessary.





































        32]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[LESSON 3 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 8




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask students the questions below to check their knowledge.
               – Do you think there can be more life in other planets?
               – Phobos and Deimos are…..

               – Which one is the red planet?
               – The hottest planet is……

        Presentation (10min):

        Use the dialogue sheet below to practice. Ask students to repeat it with a friend. Later, they can come to the
        front and present it to their friends.

        Practice (15min):
        Complete pages 29,30,31 from the Activity Book


        End of the lesson(10min):
        Use the words from page 30 to make a story about space.
        Also, remind students about Axe-Exam and answer their questions based on the exam.

        Extra Activities:

        1.  What effects does a fan or an air-conditioner have on the temperature in a room. Discuss.  W8L3E4061
        2.  Make a spaceship using recycled materials.   W8L3E4062
               – Decide on what equipment you will use to make your space station, spaceship or satellite.

               – Choose which space object you would like to build.
               – Plan the design on paper before you start building.

               – Start building! Try to follow your original design as much as possible but it’s ok to make changes as you go.







































                                                                                                              33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[LESSON 4 - EPISODE 4 | The Planets                                                              week 8




        Warm up (5min):

        Ask them what a watchman is. What is his/her job?

        Presentation (15min):
        Put some postits on the board which have different words on it. Ask a students to leave the classroom. Take
        one postit out and ask the student to come back inside. Ask him/her to guess which word it was and make a
        sentence with it.

        Practice (10min):

        Ask students to finish the line cancel ….. what? What can they cancel. Go around the classroom to get answers.
        Cancel the Show. Cancel the lesson. Cancel the program etc.

        End of the lesson (10min):
        Check the Activity Books.


        Extra Activities:
        1.  Do a Sun experiment and take a video of it. Present it to the class.  W8L4E4063
               – 2 identical drinking glasses or jars

               – Water
               – Thermometer
               – 2 elastic bands or some sellotape

               – White paper
               – Black paper
        Instructions:

               – Wrap the white paper around one of the glasses using an elastic band or sellotape to hold it on.
               – Do the same with the black paper and the other glass.

               – Fill the glasses with the exact same amount of water.
               – Leave the glasses out in the sun for a couple of hours before returning to measure the temperature of the
              water in each.
        2.  Any questions about the exam? Revise the episodes and words.  W8L4E4064

        Project:
        Play True or False! Read the Pluto Statistics with the students and ask them to say true or false. Then, check the
        correct facts together.






















        34]]></page></pages></Search>